# 哈喽大家好
Hello everyone
# 今天我伯爷又有一块肉没有卖完
Today my uncle has a piece of pork that he did not sell
# 今天我们来炒一个鱼香肉丝 家庭版的
Today we can make a homestyle Sichuan Yuxiang Shredded Pork
# 煮好了这样切（肉）要散噶
If you slice (the meat) this way it might become loose once cooked
# 嗯
Yeah
# 我们这样一片一片的这样片开了再切丝
We first slice the pork like this and then julienne
# 嘿 切这个肉片你的技术还来得到火
Hey, the way you cut this meat shows your knife skill is very good
# 这个很简单
This is very easy
# 很简单 没整（切）过的整不到这么薄
Very easy? You can not slice it this thin if you did not practice
# 这是厨师刀工的必修之课
Just some basic knife skills of a chef
# 哦
Okay
# 这哈子把它横过来直接切丝丝
Now we put the meat side way to julienne
# 切起好长根哦
This is very long
# 打斜刀撒 肯定你打竖刀切起就长了哦
Cut it sideways, you slice it vertically it will be long
# 好 现在肉丝切好了
Okay now the meat is cut
# 这个一斤的肉切出来还是不少哦你看
500g of pork is a decent amount
# 那当然了
Yes of course
# 好 我们现在开始腌肉 先把肉腌了
Okay, now let’s marinate the pork
# 我们肉丝的话这个盐一定要少放一点
For the pork juliennes, we need to be careful and not putting too much salt in there
# 放多了的话它会跟其他的味道抢味
If you put too much it will overwhelm other flavors
# 然后再放点料酒 料酒也不宜太多
Then we add some Chinese cooking wine, we should not put too much
# 然后我们给它抓一下 因为家庭做的话就简简单单的是吧
Then we mix them well, because this is homestyle dish we will do it the easy way
# 你还是要打蛋啊
Are you adding eggs?
# 要打蛋
Yes, I am adding egg
# 然后再打一个全蛋
Then adding a whole egg
# 家庭里面没有必要只放蛋清
Homestyle recipe. No need to add egg white only
# 你如果只放蛋清的话那这个蛋黄干什么呢
Otherwise, what are you going to do with the yolk?
# 蛋黄就只有丢掉 丢掉就浪费了
All you can do is throwing it away, which is wasteful
# 好 略微抓一下
Okay now we mix it a little more
# 然后再放跟蛋黄等量的干淀粉
Adding some corn starch, about the same amount as the egg yolk
# 淀粉也不可以太多
We cannot put too much corn starch either
# 再给它抓一下
Now mix it a little more
# 这个抓匀了之后再放一点油 油放进去给它保一下
Once we mix it well, we add some oil to wrap them up
# 油放进去之后里面的水份不会被蒸发出来 就是把它封锁住了
Once we add the oil the moisturizer will not vaporize. Oil can seal it up
# 待会儿下锅的时候这些肉丝也不会全部粘连在一起
Later on, when we add the juliennes into the wok, they will not stick together
# 现在就给它轻轻地捞一下
Now we pick them up a little bit
# 好 这下就可以了
Okay, now we are done
# 简单版本的肉丝就腌好了
Easy version meat marination is finished
# 这个腌法特别适合家庭用
This marination approach is very good for family cooking
# 有很多粉丝说这个鱼香肉丝为什么没有鱼
Lots of fans are asking why there's no fish in "Yuxiang" (literally "fish flavor") Shredded Pork
# 我想跟你们说的就是这个鱼香肉丝并不是里面一定要有鱼
I just want to tell you that this dish does not need fish
# 它只是说以前这个菜吧 是用做鱼的辅料和肉丝一起炒
It is because back then, we use the ingredients for fish dishes to cook the pork
# 然后我们来切这个木耳
Now let’s slice the wood ear mushrooms
# 木耳我们切得时候最好把它卷起来
While slicing the wood ear mushrooms, it’s better if we curl them up
# 卷起来切更均匀
You can slice them more evenly if you curl them up
# 这样子切起跟海带丝样
It looks like slicing kelp
# 是
Yes
# 然后切这个莴笋
Now we are slicing some celtuce
# 加莴笋其实就是配它的绿色
Adding celtuce is just to add some green color
# 有青有绿有黑有白
We got some green, some black and some white
# 还有红的
And red
# 嗯
Yeah
# 莴笋可以适当的长一点 因为它会软
We can slice celtuce a little longer because it gets soft
# 好了 现在切点红萝卜
Okay, now we slice some carrot
# 好 配料就配好了
Okay, now all other ingredients are ready
# 现在再切一点料头
Now we prepare some aromatics
# 我们准备了一点泡椒 我伯爷自己泡的
We prepared some pickled chili, my uncle made it himself
# 他不能吃辣 所以就选了一个大的 大的就不辣
He can not really eat too spicy, so I am going to pick a large one. Large ones are not spicy
# 这个海椒就没得好辣的
Yeah, this chili is not very spicy
# 然后横着把它切碎
Now we put them side ways and chop them finely
# 辣椒切好了
Now we finish preparing the chili
# 大蒜我们给它剁碎
Now we mince the garlic
# 鱼香肉丝里面大蒜的比例是姜的3倍
For Yuxiang sauce, the amount of garlic is 3 times as much as the ginger
# 然后我们再拍一块姜
Then as add a piece of ginger
# 这个姜还不是要配的合适啊 是夹（涩）口的就不好干
We need to pick the right ginger, right? If it's bitter, it tastes bad
# 是
Yes
# 好
Okay
# 我们料也配好了 辅料也切完了
Now we've prepared all the ingredients and aromatics
# 现在就还要调一个汁
Now we need to make the sauce
# 我们现在在碗里加一点盐
Now we are adding a little salt in the bowl
# 然后加几勺白糖
Then adding a few spoons of sugar
# 糖的话可以稍微多一些 大概有30克
We can add more sugar, about 30g
# 然后我们加一点醋 醋的话跟糖基本上是1:1
The we add some vinegar, the ratio of vinegar to sugar is pretty much 1:1
# 再加点生抽中和一下这个味道
Then adding some light soy sauce to neutralize the taste
# 然后再加一点点水
Then add some water
# 最后再加点这个干淀粉给它搅拌均匀
At last we add some corn starch and mix it well
# 好 可以了
Okay now we are good to go
# 来嘛 四伯爷帮我拿过来一哈
Come here, Uncle help me get that
# 加入少许明油
Now we add some oil
# 尝哈看 四伯爷
Have a taste uncle
# 试哈看嘛
Try it out
# 很下饭这个菜
It goes very well with rice
# 有点酸有点甜有点辣有点咸有点鲜
It is a little sour, sweet, spicy, salty and savory
# 真的啊
Really
# 嗯
Yeah
# 好干
Tasty
# 最入味的就是这个红萝卜
All the flavors are in the carrot
# 你吃出来没
Did you taste it
# 红萝卜吗
You mean carrot
# 嗯
Yes
# 安逸
Nice
# 我们这个鱼香肉丝最大的一个特点就是很下饭
One thing about this dish is that it goes extremely well with rice
# 因为它酸酸甜甜的又有点辣味
Because it is sweet and sour as well as a little spicy
# 这几个（配菜）味道吃起还多舒服吃起
And the other ingredients also taste very good
# 安逸 这个味道舒服
Nice! The taste is satisfying
# 好 本期视频就到这里
Okay, this is all for today’s video
# 大家可以尝试一下 看一看我之前拍的鱼香肉丝
You can try all the other recipes I made for this same dish
# 但是这个的话就是一个家常菜 就是在家里面自己炒一炒可以
But this recipe is more suitable for home cooking. Totally a homestyle dish